<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stevedore – Documentation v0.11</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation v0.11 on Stevedore</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Getting Started</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/getting-started/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Reference guide</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/reference-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/reference-guide/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Contribution Guidelines</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/contribution-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/contribution-guidelines/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="contributing-to-stevedore">Contributing to Stevedore&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thank you for your interest in contributing to Stevedore! All contributions are welcome, whether they are bug reports, feature requests, or code contributions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before contributing to Stevedore, you should:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fork the repository.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clone the repository to your local machine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set up a development environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new branch for your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-contribute">How to Contribute&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-reports">Bug Reports&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you find a bug in Stevedore, please report it by creating a new issue on our GitHub repository. Please include as much information as possible, including a description of the bug, the steps to reproduce it, and any error messages you received.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="feature-requests">Feature Requests&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you have a feature request, please create a new issue on our GitHub repository. Please include a detailed description of the feature, as well as any relevant use cases or examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="code-contributions">Code Contributions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you would like to contribute code to Stevedore, please follow these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Create a new branch for your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submit a pull request.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Please ensure that your code adheres to our coding standards, that all tests pass before submitting a pull request, and you update the project &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/blob/main/README.md">README&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/gostevedore.github.io">documentation&lt;/a>, and the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/blob/main/RELEASE_NOTES.md">RELEASE_NOTES&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="coding-standards">Coding Standards&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When contributing code to Stevedore, please adhere to the following coding standards:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use clear, descriptive variable and function names.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use comments to explain complex code.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Follow the existing code style, including indentation and formatting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Write tests for your code.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="issue-management">Issue Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We use GitHub to manage issues and feature requests. To report a bug or request a feature, please create a new issue on our GitHub repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="documentation">Documentation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Documentation is an important part of the Stevedore project, and we rely on contributions from our community to keep it up-to-date. If your contribution involves changes to the behaviour of the Stevedore project, please make sure to update the documentation accordingly. This could include updating the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/blob/main/README.md">README&lt;/a> file, adding or modifying usage examples, or creating new &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/gostevedore.github.io">documentation&lt;/a> pages as needed. We encourage all contributors to participate in improving the documentation, as it helps ensure that the project is accessible and useful to as many people as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thank-you">Thank You&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thank you for your interest in contributing to Stevedore! All contributions are appreciated.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>