<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stevedore – Documentation v0.11</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation v0.11 on Stevedore</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Getting Started</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/getting-started/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Reference guide</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/reference-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/reference-guide/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Docs: Examples</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/examples/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Explore a variety of practical examples that demonstrate the capabilities and usage of Stevedore. These examples provide a cumulative learning experience, building upon one another to deepen your knowledge of Stevedore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each example focuses on a specific scenario or use case, guiding you through the necessary steps to achieve the desired outcome. By working through these examples, you will gain hands-on experience and valuable insights into building and managing Docker images with Stevedore. They will empower you to leverage Stevedore&amp;rsquo;s powerful features and enhance your projects with confidence.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="list-of-examples">List of examples&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Example&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/01-basic-example">01-basic-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example aims to introduce you to Stevedore and its basic concepts and commands. It follows the &lt;a href="https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/getting-started/quickstart/">quickstart guide&lt;/a> from the documentation, which serves as a starting point to get familiar with Stevedore.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/02-wildcard-version-example">02-wildcard-version-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example serves as an introduction to the &lt;a href="https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/getting-started/concepts/#wildcard-version">wildcard version&lt;/a> feature in Stevedore.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/03-envvars-credentials-store-example">03-envvars-credentials-store-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example demonstrates how to use environment variables as the &lt;a href="https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/reference-guide/credentials/credentials-store/">credentials store&lt;/a> in Stevedore.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/04-multiple-apps-example">04-define-multiple-apps-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example showcases how to define and manage multiple applications in Stevedore, allowing you to build and push their Docker images.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/05-build-on-cascade-example">05-build-on-cascade-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example demonstrates the concept of building images on a cascade in Stevedore. It showcases how to create a foundational image with a common configuration and then build multiple applications using that image as a base, streamlining the image building process and ensuring consistency across the applications.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/06-git-build-context-example">06-git-build-context-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example illustrates how to utilize the &lt;a href="https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/reference-guide/builder/docker/#git-context">Git build context&lt;/a> feature in Stevedore. It demonstrates the ability to specify a Git repository as the build context, allowing you to directly build images from a specific branch, tag, or commit.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/07-inject-dockerfile-example">07-inject-dockerfile-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example showcases the capability of creating a unique build context from separate sources. One of those sources is used to inject a Dockerfile used to build the Docker image.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/08-create-semver-tags-automatically-example">08-create-semver-tags-automatically-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example showcases how to use the SemVer specification to create automatically new image tags for a Docker image.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/09-custom-variables-mapping-example">09-custom-variables-mapping-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example demonstrates the usage of custom variables mapping in Stevedore, allowing for flexible configuration and customization of build arguments provided to the Dockerfile.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/10-use-ansible-playbook-driver-example">10-use-ansible-playbook-driver-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example demonstrates the usage of the &lt;a href="https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/reference-guide/driver/ansible-playbook/">Ansible playbook driver&lt;/a> in Stevedore, enabling you to build and publish Docker images using Ansible playbooks.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/11-promote-images-example">11-promote-images-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example highlights the image promotion feature in Stevedore, demonstrating how to promote Docker images from one Docker registry to another.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/tree/main/examples/2-copy-images-from-dockerhub-example">12-copy-images-from-dockerhub-example&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This example illustrates how to copy Docker images from Docker Hub to your local Docker registry using Stevedore, allowing you to have a local copy of the desired images for offline or restricted environments.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Docs: Contribution Guidelines</title><link>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/contribution-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gostevedore.github.io/docs/docs-v0.11/contribution-guidelines/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="contributing-to-stevedore">Contributing to Stevedore&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thank you for your interest in contributing to Stevedore! All contributions are welcome, whether they are bug reports, feature requests, or code contributions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before contributing to Stevedore, you should:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Fork the repository.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clone the repository to your local machine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set up a development environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a new branch for your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-contribute">How to Contribute&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-reports">Bug Reports&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you find a bug in Stevedore, please report it by creating a new issue on our GitHub repository. Please include as much information as possible, including a description of the bug, the steps to reproduce it, and any error messages you received.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="feature-requests">Feature Requests&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you have a feature request, please create a new issue on our GitHub repository. Please include a detailed description of the feature, as well as any relevant use cases or examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="code-contributions">Code Contributions&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you would like to contribute code to Stevedore, please follow these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Create a new branch for your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make your changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submit a pull request.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Please ensure that your code adheres to our coding standards, that all tests pass before submitting a pull request, and you update the project &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/blob/main/README.md">README&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/gostevedore.github.io">documentation&lt;/a>, and the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/blob/main/RELEASE_NOTES.md">RELEASE_NOTES&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="coding-standards">Coding Standards&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When contributing code to Stevedore, please adhere to the following coding standards:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use clear, descriptive variable and function names.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use comments to explain complex code.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Follow the existing code style, including indentation and formatting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Write tests for your code.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="issue-management">Issue Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We use GitHub to manage issues and feature requests. To report a bug or request a feature, please create a new issue on our GitHub repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="documentation">Documentation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Documentation is an important part of the Stevedore project, and we rely on contributions from our community to keep it up-to-date. If your contribution involves changes to the behaviour of the Stevedore project, please make sure to update the documentation accordingly. This could include updating the &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/stevedore/blob/main/README.md">README&lt;/a> file, adding or modifying usage examples, or creating new &lt;a href="https://github.com/gostevedore/gostevedore.github.io">documentation&lt;/a> pages as needed. We encourage all contributors to participate in improving the documentation, as it helps ensure that the project is accessible and useful to as many people as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thank-you">Thank You&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Thank you for your interest in contributing to Stevedore! All contributions are appreciated.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>